作詞・作曲・編曲 初音ミク
本当の声はいつだんだって 正しい道を照らしてる
何だって疑ってるから とっても強く信じてる
心臓が動いてることの 吸って吐いてが続くことの
心がずっと熱いことの 確かの理由を追う
黒の向こうの銀河のように どっかで失くしたキリップのように
生まれる前の歴史のように 君が持っているから
それだけわかってる わかってる
僕だけわかってる わかってる
Ni-ня-n-Ni-n-Yare Nhin-n-Shaw-g sentir
Nih-n-Ni-n-Niare Nhin-Shaw-gir
There you go, runみ to your home
These pictures Uk the soul
The monster spidges that he is on the way
Immerse my use to protect
Nih-n-n-Gakug and Nhin-Shaw-gi
So
Let's go!
What's the matter, kid? First time eating grilled eel? It's delicious, right?
If you want to be first class, you gotta eat first class food. Am I right?
Well, I am the one paying for it.
Oh, for crying out loud. Don't be such a stiff. Talk about a party pooper. You're gonna ruin the taste of my beer.
Well, Koda is your foster father, after all.
He was also a prized pupil. Really strong, but like you, he had no personality whatsoever.
That reminds me of that daughter of his. A real darling, if you know what I mean.
She's strong-willed, all right, and as beautiful as hell.
But she sure is scary. She's gonna be a real heartbreaker. A true femme fatale.
I bet she secretly tormented you the whole time you lived under the same roof.
But you know, I think all women are pretty scary. You should meet my wife. She's terrifying.
That's scary?
Forget it. It's making the booze bad.
I know. Hey, we need the sake menu over here, please.
Oh, good. They've got my favorite kind here. It's the best. Soul of Aizu. A specialty from my hometown.
It smells so good.
You know what people in Tokyo call those of us from Fukushima?
They say we're stubborn, too serious, and bullheaded.
But we're really just traditional and aware of our surroundings.
Ah! They don't understand the true soul of Fukushima.
Let's go back to the year 1643.
A minor feudal lord was recognized for his shrewdness and honesty by the third Tokugawa shogun.
The shogun granted him a very generous reward, which made him the first-generation feudal lord of Aizu.
That was the feudal lord Masayuki Hoshina.
He was known as a truly wise and just ruler.
And he wasn't only an administrator.
He was the adjunct to the fourth Tokugawa shogun.
Within the shogunate administration, he proposed important policies for the greater good.
To provide Edo citizens with potable water, he created improvements to the river system.
He decreed that neighborhood dwellings should be protected from fire by widening the streets from 35 to 60 feet and establish main streets as fire breaks.
When a plan was proposed to rebuild the burnt tower of Edo Castle, he rejected it, saying peace reigns in the land.
We shouldn't waste the funds.
Oh, how decisive and manly he was.
He is the pride of Aizu.
I'm sure you've heard of the pension system.
Masayuki came up with that as well.
He also created a law for rice distribution.
He had rice stored in granaries in case of famine.
And anyone 90 years or older would receive free rice regardless of their social status.
And to this day, we still use the great pension system he enacted then.
Masayuki stood for the welfare of the people.
His spirit overflowed with benevolence.
Even now, his great efforts support the well-being of all Fukushima citizens.
Now do you see what I'm saying?
Then let's continue by going forward 250 years to the time of the Japanese Revolution.
Wait, it's not over. You're not done yet.
But first, I'll have another bottle of the soul of Aizu.
Woo!
Nice!
So where did I leave off?
Oh, that's right.
Did I tell you about my grandson?
What the hell?
What about the Japanese Revolution?
And the souls of the people from Fukushima?
Thank you. Please come again.
All right. Let's go somewhere else for drinks.
Oh, man. He's plastered.
Just like a typical town drunk.
Did you say you want to go somewhere else?
No way. I'm going home.
I'm all out of money.
Come on.
What kind of winner goes home before the loser does?
I'll pay for the next one.
I know a place.
Stagger. Limp. Crack!
Careful!
You gotta watch it when you go downstairs.
Yeah.
Right. Sorry.
I guess the booze just goes straight to my legs these days.
His arm is so thin.
The arm of a man who's held nothing but shogi pieces for 40 years.
I hear...
Mr. Matsunaga will finally retire.
I had a feeling I couldn't win.
I knew in my gut that I didn't have any chance of winning today's match.
The only thought I had was, what can I do to not look like a fool when I lose to this kid?
You probably didn't know me before the match, but I've known about you for a while.
After all, you were the fifth middle school student in history to become a pro.
I've been playing shogi professionally for 40 years, and I don't have a single record to show for it.
Your accomplishments are both astonishing and frustrating for me.
I saw you as death.
As if you were the Grim Reaper who had come to close the curtain on my life as a professional shogi player.
I was frightened of you, and I was disgusted with myself for even feeling that way.
But then, the moment I saw you sitting up straight in the matchroom, I had a thought.
What a beautiful young Grim Reaper sent to take me from this game.
If you please.
If someone was going to close the curtain on me, I couldn't have asked for anyone better.
I thought I'd at least give one more good fight before fading away.
And yet, even so,
something inside of me broke free.
I don't want to die.
Here I was at the end of my career, ruining my legacy, struggling to keep up against a prodigy.
A single thought welled up from within me.
I don't want to lose.
No matter what, I just don't want to lose.
That was my crazed line of thought at the time.
Mr. Matsunaga.
Do you still love shogi?
I don't know.
How the hell would I know?
When I'd win, I was so happy I wanted to shout with joy.
But when I lost, it was agonizing, like someone stomping on me with muddy boots.
I was tormented by the feeling that nobody wanted me to be part of this world.
And yet, I just couldn't bring myself to quit.
This feeling.
How can I even begin to express the way I feel in words?
Hello?
Rey, where are you?
I figured you might be depressed, so I thought I'd try to cheer you up.
I heard.
You won today.
Oh well, it's win or lose after all.
Just know it's not your fault.
So...
Mr. Matsunaga isn't quitting.
He won't stop playing shogi.
Hold on a minute.
What does that even mean?
Rey?
Well, let's go.
Okay.
Come on, stand up.
Hey, would you help me explain all of this to my wife and daughter?
I've got to tell them that I've decided not to retire.
They must be really worried about you.
Shogi players do need physical strength.
I don't ever want to quit.
Because if I do...
I won't be a big shot at home anymore.
I've never helped with any of the housework saying that I needed to focus on Shogi.
I certainly can't quit now.
If I do, my family will destroy me.
So that's why you're not quitting?
My blood runs cold just thinking about it.
Huh?
Right.
From now on, you're doing the housework.
And I'll even train you how to do it.
Hey, father.
It's your turn to give your grandson a bath.
Oh, the horror.
They'll make me do dishes, laundry, and change my grandson.
You should be happy to help out any way you can.
It's only fair.
I don't wanna...
Don't say that.
Families should help each other out.
Do I have to teach you how to do housework now?
I don't wanna...
No matter what anyone says, I don't wanna do it!
When did it start to hurt?
When did Christmas become such a painful holiday for me?
Dad, can we open them now?
Whoa, it's a new game bomb!
So what do you think, Ray?
I love it, really, it's great!
Which is better for a final Christmas memory, a winner or a loser?
March comes in like a lion.
You might not watch next time.
Excuse me?
That's crazy.
Thank you.